Ethan Frigon

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

ethan.frigon@gmail.com

508-846-7233

Los Angeles, CA

<u>GitHub</u>

LinkedIn

<u>Portfolio</u>

Skilled fullstack developer who's built several applications in the MERN stack and is always excited to learn new technologies. Team player with experience in software implementation, startup marketing, and digital media customer experience at companies both large and small. Away from the monitor, an avid cyclist, occasional brewer, and huge basketball fan. Excited to join a team of intelligent, thoughtful developers who strive to get things done.

SKILLS

JavaScript, ES6, React, Redux, Node.js, MongoDB, HTML5, CSS3, Git, GitHub, NPM, REST APIs, PostgreSQL, jQuery, Sass, Python, TDD with Mocha, Chai, Jasmine, and Enzyme.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

<u>DOWNTHEBLOCK</u>: Your neighborhood is now at your fingertips

- Engineered geolocation-based forums and direct messaging, enabling users to post and chat with nearby neighbors in real time using a clean, responsive interface with an intuitive user experience
- Architected an API with an Express framework to process accounts, posts, comments, and messages in a database and utilized JWT-based authentication to persist user sessions, encrypt and retrieve passwords

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS3, Sass, React, Redux, Socket.io, Node, Express, JWT, Passport, bcrypt.js, Mongoose, MongoDB

SPANISHX: Have fun while learning Spanish

- Engineered quiz-based front-end which serves users Spanish words to facilitate learning
- Built an API to process user input and created an algorithm based on the concept of spaced repetition to display new words to the user based on past answer history

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS3, React, Redux, Node, Express, JWT, Passport, bcrypt.js, Mongoose, MongoDB

<u>VACATIONBRAIN</u>: Find your next great vacation destination!

- Created front-end that enables users to ask for and give travel recommendations to the VacationBrain community
- Architected an API to process trips, suggestions, and users in a database and utilized JWT-based authentication to persist user sessions, encrypt and retrieve passwords

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS3, React, Redux, Node, Express, JWT, Passport, bcrypt.js, Mongoose, MongoDB

EXPERIENCE

Implementation Specialist

JAZVA

Los Angeles, CA

January-September 2018

- Onboarded and trained new ecommerce clients of all sizes (from one-person businesses to daily multi-million dollar sales operations) at all stakeholder levels (from founders to warehouse workers) on usage of full suite of software
- Migrated client product and sales data, including third-party extensions to marketplaces, direct sales websites, and accounting software
- Scoped and owned roadmap items on behalf of the Product team for any additional client requests (custom software options, EDI implementations, etc.)

STARTENGINE

Los Angeles, CA

Customer Research Manager

September 2017-January 2018

- Owned all research efforts to identify companies eligible to list on the StartEngine equity crowdfunding platform.
- Wrote and A/B tested email subject lines, content, and copy to drive identified companies down the sales funnel and tested and deployed new email delivery tools for better deliverability and to align with company strategy
- Managed and produced weekly workshop with Business Development team, driving attendance via email strategy

Ethan Frigon

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

ethan.frigon@gmail.com

508-846-7233

Los Angeles, CA

GitHub

LinkedIn

<u>Portfolio</u>

THE WALL STREET JOURNAL

Customer Experience Architect

New York, NY & Los Angeles, CA

July 2015-July 2017

- Defined the optimal customer experience across new digital product launches for the WSJ What's News and WSJ City iOS and Android apps as well as opportunities for improvement within existing products (WSJ, Barron's, Financial News) across all customer touchpoints
- Worked across Product, Marketing, Customer Service, and Technology departments to estimate impact of and implement improvement opportunities

Training and Operations Specialist

July 2013-July 2015

- Maintained and migrated a customer service knowledge base containing 1000+ articles, which was used by all business groups within the department, to a new platform
- Managed total reorganization of knowledge base to create easier navigation and discovery for reps, and to better track usage using Google Analytics

EDUCATION

TUFTS UNIVERSITY

BA, Economics and International Relations

May 2011

THINKFUL March 2019

Engineering Immersion

- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ¡Query, Node.is, React, Redux, and algorithms & data structures.
- Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.